So I'm here to talk to you about the walkable city.
أنا هنا لأحدثكم عن المدن المناسبة للمشي.
What is the walkable city?
ما هي هذه المدينة؟
Well, for want of a better definition,
حسنًا، للحصول على تعريف أفضل،
it's a city in which the car is an optional instrument of freedom,
فهي مدينة تكون فيها السيارة أداة اختيارية للحرية،
rather than a prosthetic device.
بدلًا من جهاز صناعي لابد منه.
And I'd like to talk about why we need the walkable city,
أود أن أتحدث عن حاجتنا لهذه المدينة
and I'd like to talk about how to do the walkable city.
كما أود الحديث عن كيفية القيام بهذه المدينة.
Most of the talks I give these days are about why we need it,
أغلب ما أتحدث عنه هذه الأيام عن حاجتنا لها
but you guys are smart.
لكنكم أنتم يا شباب أذكياء.
And also I gave that talk exactly a month ago,
لقد تحدثت عن هذا أيضًا قبل شهر
and you can see it at TED.com.
وبإمكانكم مشاهدة ذلك على موقع TED.
So today I want to talk about how to do it.
لذا فإني أريد الحديث اليوم عن كيفية القيام بذلك.
In a lot of time thinking about this,
بعد التفكير لوقت طويل في ذلك،
I've come up with what I call the general theory of walkability.
خرجت بما أسميه "النظرية العامة للمشي."
A bit of a pretentious term, it's a little tongue-in-cheek,
مصطلح رنان نوعًا ما، وساخر قليلًا،
but it's something I've thought about for a long time,
لكنه شيءٌ فكرت فيه لوقت طويل،
and I'd like to share what I think I've figured out.
وأود مشاركة ما أظن أني اكتشفته.
In the American city, the typical American city --
في المدينة الأمريكية النموذجية ...
the typical American city is not Washington, DC,
وهي ليست واشنطن العاصمة،
or New York, or San Francisco;
أو نيويورك أو سان فرانسيسكو،
it's Grand Rapids or Cedar Rapids or Memphis --
بل هي جراند رابيدز أو سيدار رابيدز أو ممفيس...
in the typical American city in which most people own cars
في المدينة الأمريكية النموذجية حيث يمتلك معظم الناس سيارات
and the temptation is to drive them all the time,
وهناك إغراءات لقيادتها طوال الوقت،
if you're going to get them to walk, then you have to offer a walk
إذا كنت تريد من الناس هناك أن يمشوا، فلابد أن تعرض عليهم مشيًا
that's as good as a drive or better.
ممتعًا كمتعة القيادة أو أكثر.
What does that mean?
ماذا يعني ذلك؟
It means you need to offer four things simultaneously:
إنه يعني أنك بحاجة لتعرض عليهم أربعة أمور في ذات الوقت:
there needs to be a proper reason to walk,
لابد أن يكون هناك سببًا مناسبًا للمشي،
the walk has to be safe and feel safe,
ولابد أن يكون هذا المشي آمنًا ويُشعر بالأمان
the walk has to be comfortable
ولابد أن يكون مريحًا
and the walk has to be interesting.
ولابد أن يكون كذلك ممتعًا.
You need to do all four of these things simultaneously,
إنك بحاجة لفعل هذه الأمور الأربعة معًا
and that's the structure of my talk today,
وهذا هو ما أبني عليه حديثي اليوم،
to take you through each of those.
سأحدثكم عن كل أمر من هذه الأمور.
The reason to walk is a story I learned from my mentors,
أما عن السبب الذي يدفعنا للمشي فقد تعلمته من معلمي،
Andrés Duany and Elizabeth Plater-Zyberk,
(أندريس دواني) و(إليزابيث بلاتر زيبرك)
the founders of the New Urbanism movement.
مؤسسي "الحركة العمرانية الجديدة."
And I should say half the slides and half of my talk today
ولابد من قول أن نصف ما سأعرضه وأتحدث عنه اليوم
I learned from them.
هو مما تعلّمته منهم.
It's the story of planning,
إنها قصة التخطيط،
the story of the formation of the planning profession.
إنها قصة تشكيل وتكوين مهنة التخطيط.
When in the 19th century people were choking
في القرن التاسع عشر عندما كان الناس مختنقين
from the soot of the dark, satanic mills,
من أدخنة المطاحن
the planners said, hey, let's move the housing away from the mills.
دعى مخططو المدن إلى إبعاد المنازل عن المطاحن.
And lifespans increased immediately, dramatically,
وبالطبع فإن أعمار الناس زادت بدرجة كبيرة،
and we like to say
وهنا أود أن أقول
the planners have been trying to repeat that experience ever since.
أن مخططي المدن ظلوا يطبقون هذه الحلول منذ ذلك الوقت.
So there's the onset of what we call Euclidean zoning,
هناك ما نطلق عليه "التقسيم الإقليدي للمناطق"
the separation of the landscape into large areas of single use.
وهو تقسيم منطقة إلى مساحات واسعة تُستخدم لغرض واحد.
And typically when I arrive in a city to do a plan,
وعادةً حينما أصل لمدينة ما لتخطيطها،
a plan like this already awaits me on the property that I'm looking at.
فإن خطة مثل هذه تكون جاهزة بانتظاري لتطبيقها.
And all a plan like this guarantees
كل هذه الخطط المشابهة تضمن
is that you will not have a walkable city,
أن المدينة لن تكون مناسبة للمشي،
because nothing is located near anything else.
لبعد المسافات بين كل منطقة وأخرى.
The alternative, of course, is our most walkable city,
البديل هو بالطبع المدينة التي تمتلك قابلية لممارسة المشي،
and I like to say, you know, this is a Rothko,
ومن المناسب لي تشبيه هذه برسومات بروثكو،
and this is a Seurat.
وهذه برسومات سورا.
It's just a different way -- he was the pointilist --
إنها طريقة مختلفة... سورا كان أسلوبه تنقيطيًا
it's a different way of making places.
ولهذا فهي طريقة مختلفة لصنع الأماكن.
And even this map of Manhattan is a bit misleading
وحتى هذه الخريطة لـ (منهاتن) تبدو مضللة بعض الشيء،
because the red color is uses that are mixed vertically.
لأن المناطق الحمراء هي مناطق مختلطة عموديًا.
So this is the big story of the New Urbanists --
إذًا فهذه هي قصة مخططي المدن الجدد؛
to acknowledge that there are only two ways
للإقرار بأن هناك طريقتين فقط
that have been tested by the thousands
تم اختبارهما من قبل الآلاف
to build communities, in the world and throughout history.
في العالم وعبر التاريخ لبناء المجتمعات.
One is the traditional neighborhood.
الأولى هي الحي التقليدي.
You see here several neighborhoods of Newburyport, Massachusetts,
هنا نرى أحياء من مدينة (نيوبريبورت) في (ماساتشوستس)
which is defined as being compact and being diverse --
وهي مدمجة في بعضها ومتنوعة،
places to live, work, shop, recreate, get educated --
هناك أماكن للسكن والعمل والتسوق وإعادة الإعمار والتعلم،
all within walking distance.
تصل إليها جميعًا بالمشي.
And it's defined as being walkable.
ولذلك فهي مدينة ذات قابلية لممارسة المشي.
There are lots of small streets.
هناك الكثير من الشوارع الصغيرة.
Each one is comfortable to walk on.
بالإمكان المشي فيها بكل راحة.
And we contrast that to the other way,
الطريقة الأخرى هي على النقيض من ذلك،
an invention that happened after the Second World War,
الابتكار الذي حدث بعد الحرب العالمية الثانية،
suburban sprawl,
الزحف العمراني،
clearly not compact, clearly not diverse, and it's not walkable,
من الواضح أنه غير مدمج ومتنوع، وبالتالي ليس قابلًا لممارسة المشي،
because so few of the streets connect,
لأن هناك شوارع قليلة فقط متصلة،
that those streets that do connect become overburdened,
ولذلك هي مزدحمة،
and you wouldn't let your kid out on them.
ولن نجعل أطفالنا يخرجون فيها.
And I want to thank Alex Maclean, the aerial photographer,
أريد أن أتقدم بالشكر إلى المصور الجوي (أليكس ماكلين)،
for many of these beautiful pictures that I'm showing you today.
على هذه الصور الجميلة التي أعرضها اليوم.
So it's fun to break sprawl down into its constituent parts.
إذًا من الجميل أن تقسّم التمدد إلى أجزاء رئيسية.
It's so easy to understand,
الآن سيكون من السهل فهم
the places where you only live, the places where you only work,
الأماكن المخصصة للسكن فقط، والأماكن المخصصة للعمل،
the places where you only shop,
والأماكن المخصصة للتسوق،
and our super-sized public institutions.
ومؤسساتنا العامة الفائقة الحجم.
Schools get bigger and bigger,
المدارس أصحبت أكبر،
and therefore, further and further from each other.
ولذلك فهي بعيدة عن بعضها البعض.
And the ratio of the size of the parking lot
وبمقارنة المساحة المخصصة لمواقف السيارات
to the size of the school
إلى مساحة المدرسة
tells you all you need to know,
سوف تعلمون بشكل كاف
which is that no child has ever walked to this school,
أنه لا يوجد طفل يمشي إلى مدرسته،
no child will ever walk to this school.
لن يمشي أي طفل إلى هذه المدرسة.
The seniors and juniors are driving the freshmen and the sophomores,
الكبار والصغار، المستجدين والمتقدمين، كلهم يقودون السيارة،
and of course we have the crash statistics to prove it.
وبالطبع فإن نسبة الحوادث تثبت ذلك.
And then the super-sizing of our other civic institutions
ثم لننظر في مساحات الأماكن العامة والمدنية الواسعة جدًا
like playing fields --
مثل الملاعب،
it's wonderful that Westin in the Ft. Lauderdale area
من المذهل أن يكون في فندق (ويستن) في مدينة (فورت لاودردال)
has eight soccer fields and eight baseball diamonds
ثمانية ملاعب كرة قدم، وثمان صالات لكرة السلة
and 20 tennis courts,
وعشرون ملعبًا للتنس،
but look at the road that takes you to that location,
لكن انظر للطريق الذي يوصلك إلى هناك،
and would you let your child bike on it?
هل ستسمح لطفلك للذهاب إلى هناك بالدراجة؟
And this is why we have the soccer mom now.
لدينا أمهات مهتمات بتوصيل الأطفال للملاعب.
When I was young, I had one soccer field,
عندما كنت صغيرًا، كان هناك ملعب لكرة القدم،
one baseball diamond and one tennis court,
وآخر لكرة السلة، وآخر للتنس،
but I could walk to it, because it was in my neighborhood.
لكنني كنت أمشي إليها، لأنها كانت فقط بالجوار.
Then the final part of sprawl that everyone forgot to count:
الجزء الأخير من التمدد والذي لا يؤخذ في الحسبان:
if you're going to separate everything from everything else
إذا كنت ستُباعِد بين كل شيء،
if you want to have a walkable city, you can't start with the sprawl model.
إذا كنت تريد مدينة يستطيع الناس المشي فيها، فلن تبدأ بنموذج التمدد.
you need the bones of an urban model.
أنت بحاجة لهيكل بناء حضاري.
This is the outcome of that form of design,
هذه مخرجات نموذج التمدد،
as is this.
وهذه كذلك.
And this is something that a lot of Americans want.
هذا ما يريده الكثير من الأمريكيون.
But we have to understand it's a two-part American dream.
ولكن لابد أن نفهم أن هناك جزئين للحلم الأمريكي.
If you're dreaming for this,
إذا كنت تحلم بهذا،
you're also going to be dreaming of this, often to absurd extremes,
فأنت ستحلم بهذا أيضًا، وقد يصل الأمر لهذا العبث،
when we build our landscape to accommodate cars first.
حينما يكون بناؤنا بهدف استيعاب السيارات أولًا.
And the experience of being in these places --
سنجرّب العيش في أماكن مثل هذه...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is not Photoshopped.
ليست معدّلة بالفوتوشوب.
Walter Kulash took this slide.
(والتر كولاش) أخذ هذه الصورة،
It's in Panama City.
في مدينة (بنما).
This is a real place.
إنها مكان حقيقي وموجود.
And being a driver can be a bit of a nuisance,
ستصبح القيادة مزعجة،
and being a pedestrian can be a bit of a nuisance
وسيصبح المشي كذلك مزعجًا
in these places.
في هذه الأماكن.
This is a slide that epidemiologists have been showing for some time now,
هذه صورة يعرضها أحيانًا علماء الأوبئة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The fact that we have a society where you drive to the parking lot
الحقيقة هي أن المجتمع الذي يقود السيارة ثم يضعها في المواقف،
to take the escalator to the treadmill
ثم يصعد للمول التجاري عبر سلم الكهرباء،
shows that we're doing something wrong.
يُظهر لنا أن هناك خللًا ما.
But we know how to do it better.
لكننا نستطيع فعل ذلك بطريقة أفضل.
Here are the two models contrasted.
هذان نموذجان تم بناؤهما.
I show this slide,
أعرض هنا هذه الشريحة،
which has been a formative document of the New Urbanism now
التي هي مستند تقييمي للبناء الحضاري الجديد الآن
for almost 30 years,
إلى ما يقارب ثلاثين عامًا،
to show that sprawl and the traditional neighborhood contain the same things.
وتعرض كيف أن نموذج التمدد ونموذج البناء التقليدي كلاهما يوفر نفس الأماكن.
It's just how big are they,
لكن الاختلاف في المساحة،
how close are they to each other,
والمسافة بين هذه الأماكن،
how are they interspersed together
وكيفية توزيعها،
and do you have a street network, rather than a cul-de-sac
ونظام الطرق الذي لديك، هل هو نظام تقاطعات أم طرق مسدودة،
or a collector system of streets?
أو طرق سريعة بمختلف مستوياتها؟
So when we look at a downtown area,
حينما ننظر إلى قلب مدينةٍ ما،
at a place that has a hope of being walkable,
والتي من الممكن أن تكون مجهّزة للمشي،
and mostly that's our downtowns in America's cities
وهكذا هي في أغلب المدن الأمريكية،
and towns and villages,
والقرى،
we look at them and say we want the proper balance of uses.
فإننا نود أن يكون هناك توازن في الاستخدام.
So what is missing or underrepresented?
ترى ما الذي ينقصها لتكون كذلك؟
And again, in the typical American cities in which most Americans live,
ومجددًا فإن في أغلب المدن الأمريكية التي يعيش فيها أغلب الأمريكيون،
it is housing that is lacking.
تفتقر إلى وجود السكن في مناطق وسط المدينة.
The jobs-to-housing balance is off.
لذا فتوازن العمل والسكن في نفس المنطقة مفقود.
And you find that when you bring housing back,
وسوف تجد أنك حينما تعيد المنازل لمنطقة العمل
these other things start to come back too,
فإن أمورًا أخرى سوف تعاود الظهور،
and housing is usually first among those things.
وأن وجود المنازل هو مجرد البداية.
And, of course, the thing that shows up last and eventually
وبالطبع فإن الشيء الذي لا بد منه حتمًا
is the schools,
هو المدارس.
because the people have to move in,
لأن الناس لابد أن ينتقلوا،
the young pioneers have to move in, get older, have kids
الشباب لابد أن ينتقلوا، ثم يكبرون ويصبح لديهم أطفال
and fight, and then the schools get pretty good eventually.
وبالتالي ستصبح المدارس أفضل مما كانت عليه.
The other part of this part,
الجزء الآخر من هذا القسم،
the useful city part,
قسم المدينة النافعة،
is transit,
هو التنقّل.
and you can have a perfectly walkable neighborhood without it.
من الممكن أن يكون كل ما تحتاجه بجوارك، فتمشي إليه بدون وسائل مواصلات.
But perfectly walkable cities require transit,
ولكن حتى المدن المجهّزة للمشي تستلزم وجود وسائل مواصلات.
because if you don't have access to the whole city as a pedestrian,
لأنه إذا لم تكن هناك إمكانية للذهاب مشيًا إلى كامل المدينة،
then you get a car,
فستحتاج إلى سيارة،
and if you get a car,
وإذا احتجنا للسيارات،
the city begins to reshape itself around your needs,
فإن المدينة ستعيد تشكيل نفسها استنادًا على احتياجاتك،
and the streets get wider and the parking lots get bigger
وستصبح الطرق أوسع، والمواقف ستكون أكبر،
and you no longer have a walkable city.
وهكذا حتى تصبح المدينة غير مجهزة للمشي.
So transit is essential.
لذا فالمواصلات ضرورية.
But every transit experience, every transit trip,
لكن كل تجربة تنقّل، كل رحلة،
begins or ends as a walk,
تبدأ أو تنتهي بالمشي،
and so we have to remember to build walkability around our transit stations.
لذا لابد أن نجهّز محطات التنقّل بالأماكن المخصصة للمشي.
Next category, the biggest one, is the safe walk.
الجزء التالي والأهم هو المشي بأمان.
It's what most walkability experts talk about.
وهو ما يتحدث عنه أغلب المهتمّين بالمشي.
It is essential, but alone not enough to get people to walk.
وهو مهم، لكن الاهتمام به وحده لا يكفي لجعل الناس تمارس المشي.
And there are so many moving parts that add up to a walkable city.
هناك كثير من الأجزاء المعقّدة في المدينة المناسبة للمشي.
The first is block size.
أولها مساحة المربع السكني.
This is Portland, Oregon,
هذه (بورتلاند) بـ (أوريغون)،
famously 200-foot blocks, famously walkable.
من المعروف هناك أن المربع 200 قدم، ومن الممكن مشيها.
This is Salt Lake City,
هذه مدينة (سولت لايك)،
famously 600-foot blocks,
والمربع هناك 600 قدم،
famously unwalkable.
ولا يمكن مشيها.
If you look at the two, it's almost like two different planets,
بالنظر إلى هذين المدينتين، سنرى وكأنهما من كوكبين مختلفين،
but these places were both built by humans
رغم أن الإنسان بنى كلاهما،
and in fact, the story is that when you have a 200-foot block city,
وفي الحقيقة، أنه في مربع الـ 200 قدم،
you can have a two-lane city,
ستكون طرق المدينة ذات مسارين،
or a two-to-four lane city,
أو من مسارين إلى أربعة،
and a 600-foot block city is a six-lane city, and that's a problem.
وفي مربع الـ 600 قدم، فستكون الطرق ذات ستة مسارات، وهذه هي المشكلة.
These are the crash statistics.
هذه إحصائية للحوادث.
When you double the block size --
حينما تضاعف طول المربع السكني...
this was a study of 24 California cities --
هذه الدراسة كانت للمدن الـ24 في كاليفورنيا
when you double the block size,
حينما تضاعف طول المربع السكني،
you almost quadruple the number of fatal accidents
فإن نسبة الحوادث تتضاعف أربعة أضعاف
on non-highway streets.
في الطرق غير السريعة.
So how many lanes do we have?
إذًا، كم مسار يوجد لدينا؟
This is where I'm going to tell you what I tell every audience I meet,
هنا سأقول لكم ما أذكره لكل من أقابل،
which is to remind you about induced demand.
وأذكّركم بـمصطلح "الطلب المُحفّز"
Induced demand applies both to highways and to city streets.
"الطلب المُحفّز" يُطبّق على الطرق السريعة وشوارع المدينة.
And induced demand tells us that when we widen the streets
هذه الظاهرة تخبرنا أنه حينما نعمل على توسيع شوارعنا
to accept the congestion that we're anticipating,
لتكون كافية للازدحام المتوقع،
or the additional trips that we're anticipating
أو الرحلات الإضافية المفاجئة التي نتوقعها
in congested systems, it is principally that congestion
في نظام مروري مزدحم،
that is constraining demand,
ستخلق طلبًا أكثر،
and so that the widening comes,
وهنا يأتي مطلب توسيع الطرق،
and there are all of these latent trips that are ready to happen.
وهناك رحلات أخرى غير متوقعة قد تحدث.
People move further from work
يذهب الناس أيضًا لأماكن أخرى،
and make other choices about when they commute,
وقد يرغبون بالذهاب إلى أماكن أخرى خلال تنقلاتهم،
and those lanes fill up very quickly with traffic,
فتمتلئ هذه المسارات بسرعة،
so we widen the street again, and they fill up again.
وهنا نلجأ مجددًا لتوسيع المسارات التي تمتلئ مرة أخرى.
And we've learned that in congested systems,
لقد تعلّمنا أننا لن نستطيع استيعاب
we cannot satisfy the automobile.
كل المركبات في هذا النظام المزدحم.
This is from Newsweek Magazine -- hardly an esoteric publication:
هذه من مجلة (Newsweek) التي تُنشر على نطاق خاص:
"Today's engineers acknowledge
"اليوم اعترف المهندسون
that building new roads usually makes traffic worse."
أن بناء طرق جديدة سيجعل حركة السير أسوأ."
My response to reading this was, may I please meet some of these engineers,
تعليقي على هذا الخبر هو: هل من الممكن أن أجتمع ببعض هؤلاء المهندسين
because these are not the ones that I --
لأن هؤلاء ليسوا هم الذين...
there are great exceptions that I'm working with now --
هناك استثناءات أعمل عليها الآن،
So you add a lane, and the traffic comes,
ثم بعد إضافة مسار آخر، يعود الازدحام،
and they say, "See, I told you we needed that lane."
فيقولون: "أرأيت، لقد أخبرتكم أننا بحاجة لهذا المسار."
This applies both to highways and to city streets if they're congested.
يحدث هذا في الطرق السريعة وفي شوارع المدينة كذلك إذا كانت مزدحمة.
But the amazing thing about most American cities that I work in,
لكن الأمر المذهل الذي أجده في المدن الأمريكية التي أعمل بها،
the more typical cities,
أكثر المدن نموذجيةً،
is that they have a lot of streets that are actually oversized
أن لديهم كثير من الطرق المتضخمة
for the congestion they're currently experiencing.
بسبب الازدحام الذي يعيشونه.
This was the case in Oklahoma City,
هكذا كانت مدينة (أوكلاهوما)،
when the mayor came running to me, very upset,
حينما أتاني العمدة غاضبًا للغاية،
because they were named in Prevention Magazine
حينما وضعوا اسم المدينة بمجلة (Prevention)
the worst city for pedestrians in the entire country.
كأسوأ مدينة للمشاة في الولايات المتحدة.
Now that can't possibly be true,
لا يمكن أن يكون ذلك صحيحًا،
but it certainly is enough to make a mayor do something about it.
ولكنه يكفي لجعل العمدة يفعل شيئًا.
We did a walkability study,
درسنا إمكانية المشي،
and what we found, looking at the car counts on the street --
ووجدنا، أنه بالنظر إلى عدد السيارات في الشارع؛
these are 3,000-, 4,000-, 7,000-car counts
هنالك من 3,000 إلى 4,000 و 7,000 سيارة،
and we know that two lanes can handle 10,000 cars per day.
ونحن نعلم أن بإمكان طريق من مسارين استيعاب 10,000 سيارة يوميًا.
Look at these numbers -- they're all near or under 10,000 cars,
انظروا إلى هذه الأرقام، جميعها أقل من 10,000 سيارة،
and these were the streets that were designated
هذه الطرق كانت مخصصة
in the new downtown plan
في التخطيط الجديد لوسط المدينة
to be four lanes to six lanes wide.
لتكون من أربعة إلى ستة مسارات.
So you had a fundamental disconnect between the number of lanes
إذًا فهناك فصل أساسي بين عدد المسارات
and the number of cars that wanted to use them.
وعدد السيارات التي أرادت استخدام هذه المسارات.
So it was my job to redesign every street in the downtown
وهكذا كان عملي؛ هو إعادة تصميم كل شارع في وسط المدينة،
from curb face to curb face,
من حافة الرصيف إلى حافة الرصيف الآخر
and we did it for 50 blocks of streets,
فعلنا ذلك لـ 50 قطعة سكنية،
and we're rebuilding it now.
والآن نقوم بإعادة بنائها.
So a typical oversized street to nowhere
إذًا فالشارع المتضخم إلى ما لا نهاية
is being narrowed, and now under construction,
أصبح أضيق، وتحت البناء.
and the project is half done.
وتم الانتهاء من نصف المشروع.
The typical street like this, you know,
حينما نعمل على مثل هذا الشارع،
when you do that, you find room for medians.
فإننا نوجِد حيّز لعمل جزيرة بين الطرق،
You find room for bike lanes.
وحيّز لمسار الدراجات.
We've doubled the amount of on-street parking.
ضاعفنا كذلك عدد المواقف على الشارع.
We've added a full bike network where one didn't exist before.
بالإضافة لإنشائنا شبكة للدراجات، لم تُنشئ في مكان آخر من قبل.
But not everyone has the money that Oklahoma City has,
لكن ليس كل مدينة لديها من المال مثل ما تمكله مدينة (أوكلاهوما).
because they have an extraction economy that's doing quite well.
فهم يملكون نظام استخلاص اقتصادي يساعدهم كثيرًا.
The typical city is more like Cedar Rapids,
المدينة النموذجية مثل مدينة (سيدار رابيدز)
where they have an all four-lane system, half one-way system.
لديهم نظام مروري بأربعة مسارات، ونظام المسار الواحد في اتجاه واحد.
And it's a little hard to see,
ومن الصعب رؤية
but what we've done -- what we're doing; it's in process right now,
ما فعلناه... أو ما نفعله الآن فهو يُنفّذ الآن،
it's in engineering right now --
والعمل في الجزء الهندسي الآن،
is turning an all four-lane system, half one-way
أننا قلبنا نظام المسارات الأربعة والمسار باتجاه واحد
into an all two-lane system, all two-way,
جميعها إلى مسارين باتجاهين،
and in so doing, we're adding 70 percent more on-street parking,
وبهذا أضفنا أيضًا 70% كمواقف للسيارات على الطريق،
which the merchants love,
الأمر الذي يحبه أصحاب المحلات
and it protects the sidewalk.
ويحمي كذلك مكان المشاة.
That parking makes the sidewalk safe,
هذه المواقف جعلت المشاة في أمان أكثر.
and we're adding a much more robust bicycle network.
وأضفنا كذلك شبكة قوية للدراجات.
Then the lanes themselves. How wide are they?
وبعد هذا فما مدى وسع هذه المسارات؟
That's really important.
هذا مهم جدًا.
The standards have changed such that, as Andrés Duany says,
فقد تغيّرت المقاييس لتكون وكما يقول (أندريس دواني)
the typical road to a subdivision in America
المسافة من الطريق إلى خط المشاة
allows you to see the curvature of the Earth.
يسمح لك بمشاهدة أنحاء الكرة الأرضية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is a subdivision outside of Washington from the 1960s.
هذه قطع سكنية ومسارات في خارج واشنطن عام 1960.
Look very carefully at the width of the streets.
انظروا جيّدًا في عرض هذه الشوارع.
This is a subdivision from the 1980s.
وهذه قطع سكنية في العام 1980.
1960s, 1980s.
بين 1960 و 1980.
The standards have changed to such a degree
اختلفت المقاييس لدرجة
that my old neighborhood of South Beach,
أن جاري القديم في الشاطئ الجنوبي،
when it was time to fix the street that wasn't draining properly,
حينما أرادوا إصلاح الطرق التي لا تجف بسرعة بعد الأمطار،
they had to widen it and take away half our sidewalk,
زادوا من عرض الطريق ليشمل نصف المساحة المخصصة للمشي،
because the standards were wider.
لأن المواصفات تنص على شوارع أعرض.
People go faster on wider streets.
الناس يقودون بسرعة في الطرق الواسعة.
People know this.
السائقون يعلمون ذلك،
The engineers deny it, but the citizens know it,
والمهندسون ينكرونه، لكن الناس يعلمون ذلك.
so that in Birmingham, Michigan, they fight for narrower streets.
لذا فإن هناك مطالبات بطرق أضيق في مدينة (برمنغهام) بمقاطعة (ميشيغان).
Portland, Oregon, famously walkable,
و(بورتلاند) بـ (أوريغون) عُرفت بأنها مناسبة للمشي
instituted its "Skinny Streets" program in its residential neighborhood.
وطبّقت برنامج "الشوارع الضيّقة" في المناطق السكنية.
We know that skinny streets are safer.
لقد عرفنا أن الشوارع الضيقة أكثر أمنًا.
The developer Vince Graham, in his project I'On,
(فينس جراهام) المطوّر لمشروع (I'On)،
which we worked on in South Carolina,
الذي عملنا عليه في كارولاينا الجنوبية
he goes to conferences and he shows his amazing 22-foot roads.
يشارك في مؤتمرات ويعرض تصاميمه لطرق عرضها 22 قدم.
These are two-way roads, very narrow rights of way,
هذه طرق ذات اتجاهين، ضيقة جدًا،
and he shows this well-known philosopher,
ويعرض للجمهور هذا الفيلسوف العظيم،
who said, "Broad is the road that leads to destruction ...
الذي قال: "أن المجال الواسع طريق يقودك إلى الدمار،
narrow is the road that leads to life."
والمجال الضيّق طريق يقودك إلى الحياة."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
This plays very well in the South.
هذا يُطبّق تمامًا في الجنوب.
Now: bicycles.
الآن: الدراجات.
Bicycles and bicycling are the current revolution underway
تمثّل الدراجات ثورة حديثة
in only some American cities.
في بعض المدن الأمريكية فقط.
But where you build it, they come.
لكن متى ما خُصص لها مكان، فستجدها.
As a planner, I hate to say that, but the one thing I can say
كشخص يعمل في التخطيط، أكره قول هذا، لكن هناك أمر واحد بإمكاني قوله
is that bicycle population is a function of bicycle infrastructure.
وهو أن عدد مستخدمي الدراجات هم الأساس في البنية التحتية الخاصة بالدراجات.
I asked my friend Tom Brennan from Nelson\Nygaard in Portland
طلبت من صديقي (توم برينان) وهو من (نيلسون/نيجراد) بـ (بورتلاند)
to send me some pictures of the Portland bike commute.
إرسال بعض الصور لمستخدمي الدراجات في (بورتلاند).
He sent me this. I said, "Was that bike to work day?"
أرسل لي هذه، فقلت له: "هل هم ذاهبون للعمل؟"
He said, "No, that was Tuesday."
فأجابني: "لا، هذا مساء يوم الثلاثاء"
When you do what Portland did and spend money on bicycle infrastructure --
حينما نعمل مثل (بورتلاند) وننفق الميزانيات في البنية التحتية للدراجات...
New York City has doubled the number of bikers in it several times now
تضاعف عدد ركّاب الدراجات في مدينة (نيويورك) عدة مرات
by painting these bright green lanes.
بعد طلاء المسارات بهذا اللون الأخضر.
Even automotive cities like Long Beach, California:
حتى في مدن وسائل المواصلات الخاصّة مثل (لونغ بيتش) في (كاليفورنيا)
vast uptick in the number of bikers based on the infrastructure.
هناك زيادة طفيفة في عدد ركّاب الدراجات.
And of course, what really does it,
وبالطبع فإن السبب في هذا،
if you know 15th Street here in Washington, DC --
إذا كنتم تعرفون الشارع الخامس عشر هنا في واشنطن،
please meet Rahm Emanuel's new bike lanes in Chicago,
اذهبوا إلى مسار الدراجات الجديد بشيكاغو الذي صنعه (رام ايمانويل)
the buffered lane, the parallel parking pulled off the curb,
عُزل الممر بوضعه مباشرة بعد الرصيف، بينما سُحبت مواقف السيارات الموازية
the bikes between the parked cars and the curb --
لتكون بين ممر الدراجات وبين الطريق الرئيسي،
these mint cyclists.
هؤلاء هم الدرّاجون.
If, however, as in Pasadena, every lane is a bike lane,
لكن إذا كان كل مسار هو مسار للدراجات كما في مدينة (باسادينا)،
then no lane is a bike lane.
فلن يكون لدينا مسار مخصص للدراجات.
And this is the only bicyclist that I met in Pasadena, so ...
ولذا فهذه الدرّاجة الوحيدة التي وجدتها في (باسادينا).
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The parallel parking I mentioned --
المواقف الموازية التي ذكرتها؛
it's an essential barrier of steel
هي حاجز ضروري ومهم،
that protects the curb and pedestrians from moving vehicles.
يحمي المشاة والرصيف من المركبات العابرة.
This is Ft. Lauderdale; one side of the street, you can park,
هذه (فورت لاودردال)، بإمكانكم إيقاف سيارتكم في جهة من الشارع،
the other side of the street, you can't.
بينما لا تستطيع ذلك في الجهة الأخرى منه.
This is happy hour on the parking side.
هكذا يمضي الوقت في جهة المواقف،
This is sad hour on the other side.
وهكذا يكون في الجهة المقابلة.
And then the trees themselves slow cars down.
وجود الأشجار أيضًا يساهم في تقليل سرعة السيارات.
They move slower when trees are next to the road,
وتكون سرعتها أبطأ في حال وجود أشجار على الطريق،
and, of course, sometimes they slow down very quickly.
وقد يحدث أن يقلل السائقون السرعة بشكل مفاجئ أحيانًا.
All the little details -- the curb return radius.
كل التفاصيل الصغيرة... قطر الرصيف الخاص بعكس الاتجاه.
Is it one foot or is it 40 feet?
هل هو قدم واحدة أم 40 قدم؟
How swoopy is that curb to determine how fast the car goes
إلى أي مدى لابد أن يكون هذا الرصيف دائري ليحدد سرعة عبور السيارات،
and how much room you have to cross.
وكم خطوة تحتاج للعبور من هذا الرصيف.
And then I love this, because this is objective journalism.
لقد أعجبني هذا كثيرًا، لأنها ممارسة صحفية موضوعية.
"Some say the entrance to CityCenter is not inviting to pedestrians."
"يقول بعضهم أن المدخل لمنطقة وسط المدينة لا يهتم لوجود المشاة."
When every aspect of the landscape is swoopy,
حينما تكون كل ملامح الطرق على شكل انحناءات
is aerodynamic, is stream-form geometrics,
فستكون ديناميكية، وعلى أشكال دائرية.
it says: "This is a vehicular place."
إنها تقول لك: "هذا المكان للمركبات فقط."
So no one detail, no one speciality, can be allowed to set the stage.
بدون تفاصيل، بدون أي تخصيص يمكن السماح به لضبط إيقاع الطريق.
And here, you know, this street:
هذه الطرق كما تعلمون:
yes, it will drain within a minute of the hundred-year storm,
ستجفّ خلال دقائق، حتى لو استمرت العاصفة لسنوات،
but this poor woman has to mount the curb every day.
إلا أنه يجب على هذه المرأة المسكينة أن تتسلق الرصيف كل يوم.
So then quickly, the comfortable walk has to do with the fact
إذًا سريعًا، المشي المريح يشابه حقيقة أن
that all animals seek, simultaneously, prospect and refuge.
جميع الحيوانات تود معرفة احتمالات مهاجمتها وحماية نفسها.
We want to be able to see our predators,
نحن نود أن نكون قادرين على رؤية المخاطر،
but we also want to feel that our flanks are covered.
ولكننا نريد أيضًا أن نشعر بأن ظهورنا آمنة.
And so we're drawn to places that have good edges,
ولذا نفضّل الأماكن التي لديها أطراف أو حواف جيّدة،
and if you don't supply the edges, people won't want to be there.
إذا لم تكن هناك أطراف جيّدة، فلن تستخدم الناس هذه الأماكن.
What's the proper ratio of height to width?
إذًا ما هو المعدل الصحيح بين الارتفاع والعرض؟
Is it one to one? Three to one?
هل هو 1:1؟ أم 1:3؟
If you get beyond one to six, you're not very comfortable anymore.
إذا تجاوز المعدل 6:1 فلن تشعر بأي راحة خلال المشي.
You don't feel enclosed.
لن تجد ما يحيط بك.
Now, six to one in Salzburg can be perfectly delightful.
قد يكون من المناسب جدًا أن يكون المعدل من 1:6 في (سالزبورغ).
The opposite of Salzburg is Houston.
وهي عكس ما يحدث في (هيوستن).
The point being the parking lot is the principal problem here.
إلا أن الأماكن المخصصة لوقوف السيارات ستمثّل مشكلة رئيسية هنا.
However, missing teeth, those empty lots can be issues as well,
وحتى تلك المسارات الفارغة كما في (هيوستن) ستمثّل مشكلة كذلك.
and if you have a missing corner because of an outdated zoning code,
وإذا كان هناك طرف مفقود من الشارع بسبب نظام تقسيم المناطق القديم.
then you could have a missing nose in your neighborhood.
فقد لا يكون هناك ركن في جوارك.
That's what we had in my neighborhood.
هذا ما حدث معنا.
This was the zoning code that said I couldn't build on that site.
فبسبب نظام التقسيم القديم لم نستطع البناء في هذا المكان.
As you may know, Washington, DC is now changing its zoning
وكما تعلمون أن هناك تغيير في نظام التقسيم في واشنطن،
to allow sites like this to become sites like this.
لتغيير مواقع مثل هذه لتكون هكذا.
We needed a lot of variances to do that.
نحتاج لكثير من التنوع في هذا.
Triangular houses can be interesting to build,
البيوت المثلثة من الممكن أن تكون مناسبة وجميلة،
but if you get one built, people generally like it.
لكن إذا وجدت أحد أنهى بنائها، فسيعجب بها الناس حقًا.
So you've got to fill those missing noses.
إذًا لابد من ملء هذه الزوايا الفارغة.
And then, finally, the interesting walk:
في النهاية، فالمشي الممتع
signs of humanity.
من علامات الإنسانية.
We are among the social primates.
نحن من المجتمعات الرئيسية على الأرض،
Nothing interests us more than other people.
ولا شيء يجذب انتباهنا أكثر من البشر الآخرين
We want signs of people.
لذا نبحث عن إشارات لوجود الناس.
So the perfect one-to-one ratio, it's a great thing.
فالطريق المثالي وهو بمعدل إرتفاع وعرض 1:1
This is Grand Rapids, a very walkable city,
(جراند رابيدز) مدينة ملائمة جدًا للمشي،
but nobody walks on this street
إلا أنه لا أحد يمشي في هذا الشارع
that connects the two best hotels together,
الذي يربط بين أفضل فندقين في المدينة،
because if on the left, you have an exposed parking deck,
لأنه في اليسار يوجد سطح موقف مكشوف،
and on the right, you have a conference facility
وفي اليمين يوجد قاعة مؤتمرات
that was apparently designed in admiration for that parking deck,
والذي يبدو أنهم بنوها إعجابًا بمواقف السيارات،
then you don't attract that many people.
ولذا فإن هذا الشارع لا يجذب كثيرًا من الناس.
Mayor Joe Riley, in his 10th term, Mayor of Charleston, South Carolina,
رئيس بلدية تشارلستون، بكارولينا الجنوبية، وفي دورته العاشرة (جو رايلي)،
taught us it only takes 25 feet of building
علّمنا أن باستطاعة بناء من 25 قدم
to hide 250 feet of garage.
أن يُخفي كراجًا من 250 قدم.
This one I call the Chia Pet Garage. It's in South Beach.
أطلق على هذا كراج شيا للحيوانات الأليفة، في الشاطئ الجنوبي
That active ground floor.
ذلك الطابق الأرضي النشط.
I want to end with this project that I love to show.
أود أن أنهي حديثي بعرض هذا المشروع.
It's by Meleca Architects. It's in Columbus, Ohio.
والذي قام به مهندسو شركة ميليكا، في كولومبوس، أوهايو.
To the left is the convention center neighborhood, full of pedestrians.
لدينا في اليسار مركز المؤتمرات وهو مليء بالمشاة.
To the right is the Short North neighborhood -- ethnic,
وإلى اليمين حي "شورت نورث"، ذو الأعراق المتعددة،
great restaurants, great shops, struggling.
وبه مطاعم وأسواق جميلة تعاني
It wasn't doing very well because this was the bridge,
بسبب هذا الجسر
and no one was walking from the convention center
لم يكن أي شخص يمشي من مركز المؤتمرات
into that neighborhood.
إلى هذا الحي.
Well, when they rebuilt the highway, they added an extra 80 feet to the bridge.
وعندما أعادوا بناء الطريق السريع أضافوا 80 قدمًا للجسر.
Sorry -- they rebuilt the bridge over the highway.
عفوًا... أعادوا بناء الجسر فوق الطريق السريع.
The city paid 1.9 million dollars,
دفعت المدينة 1.9 مليون دولار،
they gave the site to a developer,
وأعطوا الموقع لأحد المطورين،
the developer built this
الذي صنعوا هذا.
and now the Short North has come back to life.
وعاد بذلك الحي الشمالي مجددًا إلى الحياة.
And everyone says, the newspapers, not the planning magazines,
كل الجرائد تقول، وليس المجلات الخاصة بالتخطيط والبناء،
the newspapers say it's because of that bridge.
الجرائد تقول أن هذا بسبب الجسر.
So that's it. That's the general theory of walkability.
إذًا، هذه هي النظريات العامة حول المدن الملائمة للمشي.
Think about your own cities.
فكروا في مدنكم.
Think about how you can apply it.
فكروا في كيفية تطبيق هذا عليها.
You've got to do all four things at once.
عليكم أن تطبقوا الأمور الأربعة معًا.
So find those places where you have most of them
ابحثوا عن الأماكن التي تجدون فيها هذه الأمور،
and fix what you can,
وأصلحوها ما أمكنكم.
fix what still needs fixing in those places.
أصلحوا ما هو بحاجة للإصلاح فيها.
I really appreciate your attention,
أقدّر لكم انتباهكم
and thank you for coming today.
وشكرًا لكم على حضوركم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)